# M. Ata Ur Rehman Shaikh

Frontend Developer - +971 55 725 0013 - atashaikh@live.com



#### **Personal Details**

Name: Muhammad Ata Ur Rehman Shaikh

Father Name: Muhammad Shahid

Nationality: Pakistani

Visa Status: Employment grace period

Marital Status: Single

Website: www.atashaekh.com

#### **Profile**

I am a result-oriented Web Developer with considerable training and enterprise experience in Website design and layout and in all stages of design, coding, and testing of Web applications and in the formation, planning, and implementation of online business ventures.

## **Objective**

To obtain a position as a web developer in a fun, fast paced, cutting edge environment that promotes teamwork and integrity and that fosters personal and professional development.

#### Skills

I have got professional skills in following tools, languages and frameworks.

HTML5, CSS3, SASS, jQuery, JavaScript, PHP, Git, Vuejs, Reactjs, Redux Toolkit, REST APIs, WordPress, Bootstrap, TailwindCSS, Material UI

# **Work Experience**

**Senior Web Developer** – ARENA (Be Unique Group)

August 2020 – October 2022

- Creating website from scratch using PHP, HTML, CSS3, jQuery, Reactjs, WordPress, Bootstrap and JavaScript.
- ✓ Developing and maintaining the front and back end functionality of websites.
- ✓ Writing cross-browser compatible code using HTML, CSS & JavaScript.
- Developing Mobile responsive landing pages using HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap & jQuery.
- ✓ Participating in group discussion with brand and graphics team to clarify the requirement of the client.

#### **Web Developer** – The Comparison DMCC (Sougalmal.com)

Nov 2019 - July 2020

- √ Handling website samacares.sa and souqalmal.com
- ✓ Creating, updating and managing graph data as per requirement in the website

#### Web Developer - BEONTOP DMCC, Dubai, UAE

June 2016 - June 2019

✓ Developing Landing pages for Adword campaigns.

- ✓ Technical optimization for websites.
- ✓ Front-end development projects from scratch.
- ✓ Creating and controlling tasks to other departments.
- ✓ Developed website based on custom CMS such as Laravel, codeigniter.
- ✓ Managed and customized websites which were based on Shopify, PrestaShop, OpenCart and Magento.

#### WordPress/UI Developer - i3Media

Nov 2014 - Mar 2016

- ✓ Front End Developement based on HTML, HTML5, CSS / CSS3, Jquery.
- ✓ Developing and maintaining the front and back end functionality of websites.
- ✓ Writing cross-browser compatible code using HTML, CSS & JavaScript.
- ✓ Developing Mobile responsive landing pages using HTML5, CSS3, bootstrap & Jquery.
- ✓ Testing and debugging of project on cross-browser & different devices like Smart Phone & tablets.
- ✓ Developing projects in bulk using resuable strategy of SASS in WordPress CMS.

#### Front End Developer – Dotis

Jan 2013 - Oct 2014

- ✓ Developing and maintaining the front and back end functionality of websites.
- ✓ Writing cross-browser compatible code using HTML5, CSS & Jquery.
- ✓ Developing Wordpress themes & Mobile responsive websites using HTML5, CSS3, bootstrap & Jquery.
- ✓ Coordinating with clients for their requirements in website development.
- ✓ Manage the deployment of projects on live servers using ftp clients.

#### **Education**

**Bachelor of Commerce** – University of Sindh

2011 - 2013

Intermedia, Computer Science — University of Sindh

2009 – 2011

Niazi Grammar High School — Niazi Grammar High School

1996 - 2007

### **Web Projects**

I have developed following projects from scratch to end.

www.myoffice.ae (React and WordPress)

www.nordichomeworx.com (WordPress ecommerce)

www.magniflex.ae (WordPress ecommerce)

www.kitchendesign.ae (React and WordPress)

www.calichemical.com (React and WordPress)

www.emirateshr.com (WordPress)

www.94-jewelry.com (WordPress)

www.executivecentre.ae (WordPress)